Oh welcome to the pedestrian stork the
nil nervous it's an artist the Carla
team and myself were not Deena I'm an
engineer the Carla team and we are going
to talk a bit about the pedestrian and
their implementations we are going to
talk about the pedestrian navigation or
we hope to populate the map how it works
some improvements with it and a bit
about the class hierarchy and then the
nil nervous we'll talk about the
pedestrian animations about how is the
model in the 3d software how to import
from Maya to real engine and read about
the blueprint of the pedestrians then we
will see some limitations and the future
world so let's start with a video to see
how the pedestrian shark right now hold
a look we have adult and children's we
have male and female with different
closeness they can cross the road
through the crosswalks and they avoid
each each other so they are great to
populate a map
so let's talk about pedestrian education
first how to populate what we can create
questions well the first thing is to
connect to the server like this and then
get the world object then we have to
find a blueprint of the pedestrian that
we want to spawn we can use this filter
with the asterisk so we will get all the
pedestrians available for us then we
have to do similar thing to find the
controller that we will apply to each
pedestrian this controller is the one
who will control the pedestrian to move
from point to point then we have to
create a point transform a transform and
the location we can use this method get
random location from navigation this
method will return a point always
available for navigation for the
pedestrian so usually it's a point that
is always in a sidewalk and then we can
move the pedestrian a bit up so to avoid
collisions with the road now we are
going to spawn the pedestrian first we
need to choose one from the list of
pedestrians that we get here we will
choose one at random then we put the
actor in the position we define here and
then we wait for a tick just to be sure
that the actor exists in the server and
now we have to spawn the controller so
we use the similar function spawn actor
will control the blueprint also an outer
point
this is not important because the
controllers need to go attach it to this
actor to this pedestrian also we wait
for another tick so the controller
exists and from this point we can use
the controller methods for example the
stunt that will add the new pedestrian
to the crowd and also we can use the
method to go to location to make the
pedestrian walk to that position
following a road and we can use the
similar method that we use before get
random location from navigation this is
with your running the script 200 times
and we will see that the pedestrians are
spawning around the map and they start
to walk to a random point throw all the
map and if they need to cross the road
they will do that always
on a cross work
okay let's move now let's talk about how
this works
well we use a an open source library
that recast the tool already
it's a knob-end source it's in github
here in this link and we use this
library because we want to all the
calculations about the pedestrians are
in the client side not in the server
side so the server don't need to
calculate anything about the pedestrian
navigation so the the recast comes with
the a user interface where we can import
our geometry or about the map it's in
obj format then we can define a specify
some parameters and then we can start
calculating all the para or all the
geometry needed for the but finding
algorithms once this is finished the
calculation we can save Beanery file
with the final results so at the end we
only need to load these final results to
be able to navigate the pedestrians but
has some limitations for us the recast
one is the size of the map cannot be
huge because it uses some grid voxel
ization to convert the map geometry to
internal structures so probably we have
to improve this part
and also it's difficult to define
different areas for the pedestrians for
example grass sidewall crosswalk of the
roads because with the ghee we have to
define by hand a polygon closed polygon
and then all the three angles inside
will be of that specific area but that
was not very helpful for us so to use
the racast at all we have to make some
improvements the first thing we had was
a plugin in the Unreal editor
it's a Karl exporter that will export we
convert the map that you have on the
detour to obj format right before recast
to ingest also we create an application
the records builder that without any
user interface just with an input
parameter the map in obj format exported
from the Karl export tab for example and
it will generate the final binary that
we need so this is great for automatic
generation of the binary file also this
binary file will be saved in the server
side and will be sent to all the clients
that meet the pedestrian also we improve
the way we can define the areas where
the pedestrians can work they are mainly
four areas one is the road the sidewalk
the crosswalk and the grass so to define
all of these areas we have to specify
specific nomenclature for example when
in the 3d software or in unreal we have
to specify starting the name convention
for that object for example this road
that we have selected start by Road Road
that means for the navigation
pedestrians
this will be a Rotarian so the same for
the sidewalk we have selected one and
start by the road sidewalk the same for
the crosswalk the crosswalk and also for
the grass the grass are bigger areas
that are like a secondary sidewalks the
pedestrian can walk there but will we
know the first option to work so let's
take a more technical look to this this
image we see the we have several
pedestrians and each one have a
controller attached to it this
controller that we use in this clip
before using this commands have four
methods that we can use the start and
the stop is to add or remove the
pedestrian from from the crowd so it's
managed automatically also the method to
make pedestrian work to a point and also
if we want to fix a maximum speed for
different pedestrians and also the
controller just to clarify that needs to
be attached to each pedestrian and this
is the class hierarchy we can start from
the from the bottom we have for example
two actors with date controller attached
it and this controller connects directly
to the walker navigation class that is
the one in charge of the updating the
crowd the pedestrians so he needs to
check if a pedestrian hostile or exist
if if it doesn't exist then will will be
removed from the crowd also he needs to
update the vehicle in the endures in the
map because the pedestrians tried to
avoid the vehicles and also update the
position of these pedestrians then the
Walker navigation needs some low-level
functions from this class the navigation
this is the class that will use the
records library and also will receive
the Beanery file for the navigation from
the server or the server will send this
content for the corresponding map and
the navigation class will load this
Venera file to the records Liberty to
use all the functionality about
navigation also we have two more classes
the walcker manager and the worker event
the worker manager is the one that will
define the road that will follow each
pedestrian to to go to a point and also
we create some specific events like for
example a stop and check that this event
happens when a pedestrian needs to cross
the road through the crosswalk
then the pedestrian will stop and check
if a vehicle is in front and we wait
until the way is free to walk and that's
all for the pedestrian navigation now
the nil novice will carry on the talk
with the pedestrian animations greetings
i'm daniel dollars I'm a developer from
the our team and I'll give you some
information about how to import
pedestrian models and animation clips
also about the bound actor class and the
way the navigations logic determines the
displayed animation sequences through
the animations routine even graph and in
grass and bled spirits tool
the distance in unreal for our pound
actors we are defined as a combination
of a skin mesh and skeletal hierarchy
they represent humans and they are
subject to navigations logic also we
have the option to control them manually
we have four based models to adults male
and female and took it boy and girl in
space model has multiple clothing
variations the poly count is about 10
20,000 triangles for the shaders we work
with PBR textures this includes clothing
subsurface skin shader and a specific
head shader about animations we use an
animation set that includes either
working running and piped cycles this
skeletal hierarchy is made of 66 bones
as I said all pedestal models share the
same skeleton of 66 bones they share
both hierarchy and naming conventions
but they have different sizes and
proportions this skeleton offers control
for a biped model there is no facial
expression only the eyes which are
controlled by bones we work with FBX
files for pedestrian models both teens
meshes and skeletons are sported from
Maya in a single file FBX file format
can include data and geometry skeleton
her keys animated channels and vertex
skinning weights imported skeletons must
be compatible and assigned to the
escapists in general acid this is our
standard pedestrian skele-toes
definition or grill these definitions
includes information to generate the
skeletal mesh physics a set animation
sequences are exported as independent
FBX files they should contain the
skeleton and animated data insight on
real they are defined by the sky
pedestrian ginger and acid when imported
the epic X must be assigned to these
efficient just like the skin geometry
the result is an animation sequence
asset we named our actors as BP Walker
pouncing on real are the way to
implement weak pedestrian actors and
both connect them to navigation logic or
cultural them manually collision
detection can be added at the bounce
capsule further detection boxes can be
added we use extra added collisions as a
death trigger and for current proximity
detection
the event graph of an animation
blueprint is the logic that rolls the
bounce states on behaviors according to
the events and function calls from the
navigation logic thus determining which
animation sequence is applied it is an
old graph and determines the animgraph
and blendspace functionality the central
core determines the pedestrian speed is
it is used for translation animation
sequences and those within a square
determines the orientation and whether
the pedestrian is a static or not the
aneema graphs animation blueprint is a
finit state machine is another hierarchy
where we can alter different clips and
define the interaction between each
other each transition has a specific
conditions to swap between States back
and forth
translation clips are implemented
through the blendspace tool orientation
clips are implemented directly these
tools bless different animation
sequences first read the active speed
information from navigations logic
through the event graph we use it to
blend the idle sequence with translation
sequences such as work and run right now
the pedestrians work from point to point
just to populate the nod each client
manages its own crowd so pedestrians of
different clients don't avoid each other
we have a small set of animations
restricted by the a vein graft and logic
we want to implement in the future new
events for pedestrians for example wait
for green traffic light at crosswalks
and custom animations sent from the
client also we are planning to add a
blue cast in the tool to be able to
handle big Maps finally we want to
improve our pedestrians visuals and
animation sequences we are studying an
approach from photography references or
3d scanned data also we want to
implement new animation States and
that's all about the destination
we hope the points covered have been
useful and don't miss that the slides
are accessible from the lobby
thank you