hi my name is Mark Garcia butch
I am sensor and simulation engineer in
color simulator and in this opportunity
I will talk about sensors and what is
new in color guarding them I will first
introduce the new RGB camera grid with
its new parameters and how to use them
but I will talk about the new sensors
and the implementations let's start with
the new RGB camera crane the main reason
behind why artistic so muddy for
detailing Al were different maps with
new assets and carrying so much about
illumination and the fireman is just
because the RVT sensor right we know how
important is the sensor for perception
we are using such a big beast like
Unreal Engine just because we want good
visual fidelity it's critical for our
project and we're constantly iterating
over this feature implemented step by
step a few months ago some of these
iterations happened leaving a good
amount of new capabilities for this
sensor the new camera supports several
useful futures which has learned
assertion different exposure modes and
depth of field all of this takes
advantage of the Unreal Engine
capabilities to ensure maximum
integration with the engine so we can
achieve good performance we're adding
new features like noise functions like
chromatic aberration but keeping mimic
within real cameras and their parameters
so we can evolve with it and maybe in
the future use dry cast or any new
rendering technology that will real can
provide I will briefly talk about these
ones you can see in this light right now
these are sun exposure modes and color
correction
ladies are shown on chromatic aberration
are the main noise functionalities for
this sensor they can be customized and
combined each other and work as expected
with all the other configuration here we
can see a video with this new feature
reduction to properly see the effect
check out this trick light in the top
right corner of the video here first we
see the normal G V then the RGB + land
assertion and exaggerated one
and now our gv+ chromatic aberration our
success rate now a combination of the
previous ones you can see the distortion
here on the corners
they also works fine with depth and also
semantic segmentation now we'll provide
two exposure types the manual one which
takes the f-stop or the inverse of the
aperture the ISO on the shutter speed
like a conventional camera and then we
have the auto exposure which takes other
parameters to achieve the effect that
you can see in the video you can see the
color of the scene is slowly adapted
depending on the bright the images
then we have the color correction to
simply achieve different color results
this can be useful for some of you that
work in perception to create some quick
and cheap variability in your data here
we play with the image temperature tint
slope Anto among this is exposed we've
exposed few other camera attributes
which can create fine details such as
type of field motion blur and blade
count and of course you can configure
all of these parameters i've just
mentioned from the client side more in
depth I will now show you how to spawn
use and configure them so for those of
you who don't know in order to rule 10
shoot a camera or an hour type of sensor
in Carla we recommend using the Python
API it is easy to use and walks out of
the box if you prefer you can still use
a C++ API too but in this case we will
focus on the Python API so first we just
get a description of the desired sensor
which is called blueprint in this case
we are searching for an RGB camera then
we just need to use the function spawn
actor which takes as a parameter the
barians blueprint the location where it
will be found and finally the parent in
case it is attached to something like a
car mentioned that the spawn transform
iterative to the parent in case it is
provided otherwise it is in world
coordinates and the sensor will be
statically placed in the world then in
order to decide what to do with this
data you will only need to call the
function listen that will set a callback
to a function this one that will be
called each time a new data right from
the sensor in this case we just only
store the data as an image into the disk
and that's it
dissolve the configuration parameters
just for the RGB camera some of them
such as the land assertion ones are
shared with other camera based sensors
like the somatic segmentation more
in-depth an explanation on what they do
can be found in our documentation in the
link below in order to use them here you
have an example of how to instantiate an
RGB camera with some of the previous
parameters in this case a filter B was
75 degrees I should repeat for the
camera of 60 and a bit of chromatic
aberration to create some nice noise
effect getting the grouping and spawning
and spawning it it is exactly the same
as before
now let me present the new sensors I
will perform a brief introduction to the
ones you can see on your screen the IMU
the radar and the DBS let's start with
the simplest one the IMU refers to an
inertial measurement unit this one is
composed of an accelerometer a gyroscope
and the compass it round on server side
it has default nice functions unlike the
other sensor the tick time is
configurable I'm sure you will find
handy to have it integrated natively
here I have made a quick and simple
visualizer using the Python API to
properly see the IMU values changing at
the left the accelerometer which tell us
the evolution of the velocity over time
we can see the three components X in red
Y in green and that in blue at the right
we have the gyroscope that shows the
rotation velocity of the sensor roll in
red pitch in green and Yao in blue you
can see hold the yolk blue line in the
gyroscope changes when the vehicle turns
also you can see the peaks in the
accelerometer when I collide with
something here
instancing and using it is basically the
same that we made before with the lgb
sensor but in this case we will sell for
the sensor dot other dot a Lemieux and
everything else is done the same except
for that in your data obviously the IMU
alongside with the GNSS takes advantage
of the new genetic knowledge system we
implement it on the server side that can
be used for all the sensor in case it is
implemented for the sensor and it makes
sense for it to have it it's like the
covalent for the lens distortion seen
before in the cameras it is prepared to
be deterministic and is computed in the
server side but can we parameterize it
from the client side so this means that
if you have multiple clients connected
to the server they all will recite the
same sensor output by default we are
using a normal distribution for that but
you can change the code to adjust the
noise for a more accurate model if this
were require adding these noise to the
atom you uses the same methodology that
adding it to the LGV cameras you only
need to set the correct attribute to the
blueprint before spelling it and again
everything else which will just work as
expected we have also dedicated some
time only firing sensor that world
competed in the client like the Genesis
and the IMU now those computers are
happening on the server side to freeze
some load from your client nodes this
also ensures that the data that you
trying are receiving is the same
regardless of the apply it noise now the
radar it is another new sensor that has
been recently added to Carla I will not
explain how a little reader works but in
short it is a detection system that uses
radio waves to determine the range angle
or velocity of the objects multiple
raters can be said to occur in order to
provide valuable information of this
running this Raider has a main loop the
one you can see on the right this is the
main detection range of an even greater
and the one we enter simulate here I
have a video where
you will see an example of the real
detection zone Carla as a visualization
the detection circle red using the color
palette on the Left white means the
object has the same ability as a radar
in relation to the rather orientation
blue means the object moves away from
the radar and red means the object is
approaching to the radar this happens
the same regardless of the radar
velocity towards the radar direction so
if my car is moving this a velocity is
another car in front of me
it will be detected as white otherwise
if a car is a Wonder and me or this is
driving towards me it will appear as red
the why our radar works is the following
giving objects with velocity the red
reduce cares about the velocity of these
objects projected in the direction what
it is facing so we will work with the
project vector of the object's velocity
with the radar direction just like that
each frame a certain amount of ray
casting is randomly shooted matching the
lope shape of the Raider the ones that
collide with their something they get
the ability of the object in relation to
the sensor velocity and this is the
information that will be received on the
client-side here I have a correct
everything to multi preview in the
previous video
once again spawning a Raider is exactly
the same but changing the blueprint you
are searching on in this case by a
sensor dot awdurdod crater it also
changes the data is received
of course our radar runs on CPU using
Unreal fakest this means it also runs on
the server side like all the other
sensors it has a configurable tick time
and some specific rather configurations
like lobe shape or the frequency the
coronal limitations are that it is not
physical accurate compared with a real
leader this is because we are not
completing the scattering or the
realistic interaction with different
materials also the raycast is not
perfect with our vehicles and palestine
since they use animated meshes we'll
still searching a way to improve it
now I'm competent is the new DBS
approach that has been resonated to
Carla this was not in a war roadmap but
since we received our community board
request we decided to include it into
our latest release the DBS is an
event-based I'm sure that basically
measures the changes of the intensity of
synchronously and can be used for
high-speed scenarios and high dynamic
range environments our implementation
runs on CPU another computation is done
in the server side as a future work and
to increase performance we could
investigate how to port it into a shader
so it will use the GPU instead and
finally you can expand it like other
sensors but in this case using sensor
camera dot DBS but what is your official
update about what we've done so far
regarding the new sensor simulation now
was a future work we're really
interested in - what on reified can
provide to carla and we want immediately
to potential a new rendering back-end
for the simulator as always alongside
the our team we will also focus on the
performance improvements and at the same
time achieving better lumination as it
is the key for realism finally if you
are into sensors and you like this
presentation I recommend you to check
out the external sense with the
vegetation done by my colleague Daniel
Santosh
so that's it I hope you enjoyed the
presentation if you want to join our
community feel free to use or this court
to direct contact with us