hi welcome to the core futures talk
excel lovin and me burn apena
we are engineers of the karla team and
we are going to talk about about
synchronous mode of it works and what is
the pixel at that time also why would
the concept of world as an app shop some
new concept and also some app extensions
that axel will will explain related to
waypoints and new function new classes
like Junction and landmark so let's
start with the synchronous and
asynchronous mode the synchronous mode
is the default one
so is the where we have the server that
it has the mine loop to create us as
many frames as he can as fast as he can
also and the clients will wait for the
friends to come but the server will not
wait for the client so the client needs
to make fast calculations because the
friends will will come one after the
other and sometimes when the client
needs to make complex calculations this
is not a good way of doing because the
client can skip frames and for that we
have the synchronous mode this one where
one of the clients for example the
client to is the one who has the mine
loop for the creation of the map their
frames and the server it's just waiting
for the tick that the client needs to
call and then when they call the client
called the tick the server will simulate
one frame and then wait again also the
other clients are waiting for the frames
and only one client is the one in charge
of doing the ethic so this is very
useful if the client to needs to make
some slow calculations one frame by one
frame so the server will wait
but for this mode to work properly we
need to define the fixed set Delta time
this is the time that the server will
simulate in each frame because the
server will wait for the terminate time
so he cannot know how much time to take
for the frame so we have to define so by
default 20 frames we are using these
these fixed Delta time that means that
50 milliseconds okay so how we do this
in source we need to connect to the
server and get the wall and then from
the wall we have the method to get
settings that will get will give us the
current settings and the synchronous
mode is a volley on if it's true or we
set as true then we are in synchronous
mode otherwise in a synchronous mode
also if we set the synchronous mode we
have to define the fixed Delta seconds
for example here 420 frames per second
and then we apply the settings from this
time because we are in synchronous mode
one of the clients will need to make the
world tick and the other clients if
there are more just wait for the tick
[Music]
okay the future work is to work on a
truly multi client synchronous mode
because right now only one client is in
charge of magnetic for the server but we
need that it several waits for all the
clients to do they take so that is
something we are working on now we are
going to see the wall a snapshot the
wall is nap shot is like a stick capture
of the of the scene of the H frame and
we have some properties like the ID of
the new frame the frame count and also
sometimes the lapse at times is the time
from the start of the simulation the
Delta seconds is the time from the last
frame the previous frame and platform
timestamp is the timestamp from the
operating system and also for all the
actors we have in the scene we have an
actor in snapshot an actor a snapshot we
have some other properties like the idea
of the actor and also some methods to
get the position or rotation the
velocity angular velocity acceleration
and also we have an estate that this
instructor that in function of the kind
the type of actor we have for actors
then the state will have some properties
or others so these are the properties
for for example a vehicle we have a
control with all the controls that are
applied in that frame and also a speed
limit if the vehicle has some speed
limit applied apply it also for the
traffic light and if it is the case the
traffic light ID and also the state
cannot see also for the Walker we have
the direction they are moving on the
speed or so if the jump command is
enabled in that frame and for the
traffic light we have the sign ID this
is the identification that comes from
the open drive so we can
relate one with the other also we have
the configuration of times 4-h state the
Pauline Dex is if the traffic light is
inside the group to know which is the
the index inside the group and also we
have the state for the traffic signs we
have only the IV from the open drive so
in code we can get the wallet snapshot
for example if we weigh wait for a tick
then we will get automatically the
wallah snapshot but we can get the wall
snapshot with this method at any time
and also if we are in a call back
waiting for on tick then we get the wall
snapshot as a parameter and also for the
actor a snapshot we have two methods in
the world snapshot we have hot actor if
that actor exists in the world snapshot
and if that is the case we can use the
fine
to get the actors nap shot of that
doctor and now axel will talk about the
new IP extensions this part of the
presentation I will talk about some of
the extensions that have been done to
the Python API so I will turn around
three topics first about the weapons
type extensions the new class Junction
and the new class number which is a way
to support open drive signals
so first of all a quick reminder of what
the weapon is
so it represents at elected point in the
road so you have this particular Lane
you have a very pointing in this
location so we left with the direction
of the of the traffic in this point the
last query wrote informations just
rotate the lanes cetera and the function
next is available to you to traverse
this the map in the direction of the
traffic so you can move in this
direction it is an abstraction so that
you don't need to worry about
complicated geometry and so on that may
be you know in in the open drive file so
to expand upon this previously you could
only use the function next to move
through the road soon which meant that
you could only move forward now we have
added the possibility to move backwards
through the previous function similar to
next you can enter the previous in a
certain amount certain distance and you
will get a new weapon corresponding to
that is the distance you need
also we have added some helper functions
next until a man's players and too late
start these give you a set of these all
these waypoints in a single call which
is you get way constant at the end of
the particular lane or until distant we
have also added the possibility to
quality to take away points using open
drive information such as go outside the
lanes ID
they will have the new class junction
which is represent an intersection in
the map
lanes split verge intersections etc so
it first some materials the first one is
the idea of this of the junction which
corresponds to the of the drive file
then there is the bounding box this is
the area that this Junction is taking in
the in the map so you can use this to
query whether there is an object within
inside an obstacle on another vehicle
etc then we have the function get
weapons which this function returns a
pair of waypoints for every lane in the
in a junction so they have the initial
position and the final position of the
of a particular lane in a junction this
allows you to guess the connectivity of
the roads wire is a real name connected
and you can get this Junction object
using the weapon so from a particular
point that is within a junction this
function will return you the
corresponding object finally we move to
the new class landmark so this is a way
to support open drive signals where it's
stopped here
traffic lights etc this is a way to
query the open drive signal record and
extract this information so the new
class lemak has several functions and
they are detailed in the documentation
here I provide some of the most
important ones the first one is the ID
the idea of a landmark response to the
signal ID to the ID of the corresponding
signal in open Drive notice that there
may be multiple landmarks with the same
ID which means that a particular signal
is having an effect in different places
in more than one road
then we have the type which is this
identifies whether a signal is stop and
yield traffic light etc the underlying
type is a string which means that you
can use a different country code if a
custom country code signal code and you
can and this class will still gather
this information that is up to you to
the tag with signal is a stop whatever
type in your in your custom code then we
have the transform which is the physical
position of the signal now we will have
the lane Bali dysfunction which this
returns a list of all those lanes with
which this particular signal is taking
effect in a particular Road
then we'll have the how to query for
this llamas how to obtain them so one
way is through the weapons so for a
particular position in the map you can
get a weapon here and search for
landmarks within a certain range then
for you get a list with all this
knowledge that you have found and you
can do whatever you need you can look
for landmarks for any type or just
filtering with a particular type here is
this an example of this so you just get
a waypoint everyone then search for
landmarks within a distance in this case
with the meters and then for the
resulting list of landmarks you can
search with its top and then do whatever
behavior you want to implement it's a
stop sign or if you want you can expand
this to support science or whatever to
support the deals or whatever other
traffic sign that you
then we have some other functions to
obtain the landmarks such as get our
landmarks in catalan up this allows you
to retrieve all the landmarks that are
defined in the open data file and you
can do the same called filtering my type
which means you can get all the all the
stops in the map with a single call or
from an ID which means you want to get
all the landmarks corresponding to a
particular traffic sign which is all the
places where this signal is taking an
effect and finally there is the
connection with the simulation so from a
landmark so the landmarks represents the
open drive signal record and then we
want to retrieve the corresponding
object in the simulation for instance a
traffic light we want to retrieve a
traffic light that we have to type those
landmarks we want to call it state we
need to get the Kerala actor
corresponding to this traffic light so
this function get traffic light you can
get this actor inquiry but its screen or
how long it takes to turn right exactly
so this is for nap doesn't the show
thank you