welcome to the data Jessie on Talk
my name is Burnett bina I'm an engineer
of the Karla team and we are going to
see one need to what we need to support
from other softwares to be able to
import into Karla
we will see two ways of doing that the
import we can use the token and we can
import from the source also we will see
how to reveal the pedestrian navigation
file and also some limitations on future
work so let's start with the
introduction video where we can see we
are using Road Runner for example and we
are we have defined a map with traffic
lights and we want to import this
exactly map into Carla or realtor like
now we see all it's working pedestrians
vehicles and traffic lights are working
fine so
[Music]
this is the general overflow we can use
any other software but at the end we we
need to export the specific data that
Karla can can understand for the
ingestion and import and we can use
Tomatoes for import we will see right
now but first we will we are going to
see what we need to sport mainly the
idea is to export two files one is the
film box file
FBX with the geometry of the map and the
other file is the open drive with a
traffic Network description of the map
also we can use a JSON file this is
optional but the important thing is that
if we the name of the JSON file will be
the name of the package that we need to
know later on to sport the the package
so if we don't specify JSON file one
will be created automatically with the
map package name so this is important as
we will see later this JSON file is like
this it's just a description of the maps
the files so for the map one we have the
FBX on the open drive and for the map 2
we have the DX on the open drive we we
can define the folder where they are but
this is automatically created if no json
file is is given so it's an optional own
so for the EDX file it's important to
use a specific nomenclature this is
important for the pedestrian navigation
to identify which are the areas where
they can work or cannot work so we have
four main areas the road for example all
the geometry for the road need to start
in one of this nomenclature rod rod rod
marking rod core or hot water for the
sidewalk we need to use the rod sidewalk
also for the crosswalk the same with
this nomenclature and the grass that is
a secondary sidewalk also need to start
with rod grass so let's see how we can
import data into Karla
we have two ways of doing one is using
the token file and also is using the
source from the github so in function of
the platform we are using for Ubuntu we
can choose one of the two but for
windows we can only import using the
source but importing this way we can do
the same that do the token so we are now
limited limited so let's start c using
the local okay so to use the token first
we need to build the docker 1 and we
have this information of the files
required required for build a docker are
in Karla util dokyun also we have some
prerequisites like six hundred gigabytes
of space
Ubuntu 16 was the minimum and also this
version of docker by 27 and also the UF
for toker model for the Python we will
use this for building the
and we have to follow these three steps
first we need to download the unreal
source we are using this command here we
see the version of the Unreal we want to
use sorry then when we have the source
of the unreal we have a second step we
use this command to compile to prepare
all the compilers and compile the Unreal
Engine the prerequisites docker file is
in this folder ready to use and the last
step is download and compile carve a
project using this command also the
Carla docker file is is here
so with these three steps we have built
the docker and it's ready to use
so now let's go to let's go to use
docker to import we are going to use two
folders one is the in folder where we
are going to copy the FBX and open the
files that we want to import and also
the JSON if we are providing one also we
are using another folder for output this
folder will be the where docker will
write the result and what we need to do
is to go to the Kerala util docker
folder and use the docker tools python
script using these arguments the input
with the input folder the output with
the output folder we are using and also
the package we want to export from the
docker that is then this is the name of
the JSON file that we are providing or
if we don't provide JSON file then this
name map package is the default one so
we are going to use this one
so at the end oaken will write in the
output folder we define the map package
tour wall with all the important files
that is this is the docker this is the
process that the docker will use Karla
source it has the Karla source
internally then execute the make import
to import the files and then they make
packets to make the package this is the
package we will get from dhaka and now
we can use Karla package that we have an
import with the import assets script so
let's see this process in a video ok
let's see the video as we saw in the
image we have the day Karla docker built
now ready we have the files to import in
the in folder also the ODE folder is
empty and now we are moving to the
folder util docker and we are going to
call the doctor with the parameters we
are going to use the docket tools right
on the screen with the input and output
folders and also the name of the package
that we want as a result now dr. is
executing making the making poor then
they make package and at the end we have
in the out folder we are going to see we
have the package that is the package
that we can import it now we are going
to see what to do with this package in
another video we have we have a Karla
package with this version and what we
need to do is to copy the package in the
import folder and just call the import
assets
the import assets just decompress the
file so now we start the server and now
we are going to load the new map with
the config script using config and the
name of the map map test in this case
okay
the map is ready we see we have the
traffic lights working they are created
in real-time with the information of the
urban ref and now we can spawn some cars
and some pedestrians there they go we
have the Pistons working and some
vehicles driving around with the traffic
lights working fine so that was working
ok
[Music]
let's move now to the other method to
import not using docker but using the
Karla source project so it's simple but
we we will see we have we need to make
an extra step so to import here we have
the software we export our files that we
need to import here we need to copy
these files in the import folder of the
Karla project and then just execute the
make important this will cook all the
files and will give us the map ready to
load in reality tour so that the
advantage of this is that we can use
unreal editor to modify the map if we
need but we need to recreate the Beanery
file for the pedestrian navigation
docker does this automatically but for
the Kara source we have to do it in a
separated way so we are going to see now
how to recreate the pedestrian area
so this process basically what it does
is with the geometry of the map that we
have we have to imported in realtor we
can load the map a new level and then we
can use the collects portal to export
the geometry in obj file also from the
open drive of the map we can parse the
open drive and get all the crosswalks
that could be defined from Road Runner
for example and finally the final obj
file will be they will be passed by a
recast builder an application with it
also and we'll create we'll create the
final binary file this binary file it's
a description of the areas where the
pedestrians can walk or not so the first
step is to load the map the important
map in the Unreal editor and then use
the car exporter to create the object of
that map the car exporter will will save
the obj file in the car loan real Carla
Fuqua for saved and then we have to copy
that obj and the open drive in this
folder Carla you till doc utils this
because here we have some scripts that
we only need to call once and all will
be generated the the open drive is
needed only if we have some crosswalks
define but if not we can free we are
free to not copy but doesn't matter
really and this is the second step that
we need to build to call this script a
build or a built in Linux
with the name of the map with of the
extension so this clip will be able to
find the map test open drive map test
@vx or VJ or whatever the this this
script will do these these steps here
basically if we have the Autodesk FBX
SDK installed and and this application
is compiled it that we provide this
source then we'll try to convert the FBX
to object but because we use the Cal
exported and we have the map in obj file
format
this step is Skype so we don't need to
install this library so the open drive
will be an per set by this script to
find all the cross walls will generate
obj with all the cross walls with this
script we merge both of edges in only
one that will be used for
miracast builder to generate the binary
file so at the end is been a file we
need to copy to the NAP navigation
folder of the map and that's it so let's
see in a video all this process we have
the files we want to import
we copying the import of the kerala
project there is no json file there and
now we have to to make an import now
it's in importing in unreal editor these
files we will see in the import folder
that initiation is there is
automatically created with the name map
pocket
okay we have all the files imported now
we need to to launch editor okay and now
we are ready to load the map the
imported map it's in the map package
inside the maps map test this is your
map
we loved okay there it is and now we
need to export in obj format using the
curl exporter the Cal exported is in the
file menu this will export all the
geometry in the saved folder so now we
are going to find the obj and we need to
copy to the other folder here is the
file we are going to make a temporary
copy and now we are going to move to the
utils docker utils the cutest list and
we need to copy here the obj and the
open drive file
okay and now we can call the build
script with the name of the map and it
will generate the Beanery file for us
okay there it is so now we have the map
test
pin this is the file we need to copy
inside the navigation folder of the map
so we are going to move to the folder
where is the map map package the package
inside maps map test and here in the NAP
folder this is the original one and this
is the new one that is bigger and we
replace okay now we are ready to run the
simulation and we will see the traffic
lights will be created at real time with
the open drive information and now we
can spawn some vehicles and pedestrians
to see that they work
okay all is working perfect
you have the pedestrians walking and
crossing the roads and the vehicles so
so let's move now to the limitations on
future work the cooking process could
file with huge Maps so we need to check
that with a very huge map and also for
the sign ingestion we we need to find a
way to identify when a traffic light
comes from the geometry from the FBX
file to remove them because we create
the traffic lights and other traffic
signs from the open drive information
and with an we don't want to plication
also the the signs that are created from
the open drive right now don't have
collisions for the pedestrians because
they are created a tree on our real time
so they are not in the binary file but
we we need to fix that and also we saw
some problems with the VX importer that
uses unreal with some alpha channels and
models with a scale it has some trouble
and that's it thank you very much for
watching