hi carla users
this tutorial shows how to build carlina
linux system
there are two types of installation in
karla one
are the release packages self-contained
binaries that run a specific version of
the simulator
the other is to directly build carla
using the github repository
the build process is a bit more tricky
but it will allow you to run karla as a
developer
using the unreal engine editor the
simulator can be run normally using the
api and all the different features but
there are some additional possibilities
first the build can be updated anytime
to run with the latest additions made by
the developers so there is no need to
wait for a release
also the build makes for greater
customization options as the simulator
itself can be modified
this obviously requires having some
understanding of from real engine
if you are only interested in using the
released features it may not be
necessary for you to make the build
give it a thought to make it clear what
your intentions are
and then if you are interested in
working with the karla build
follow this tutorial
the build process is detailed in the
karla docs the easiest way to check it
out is going to our website
karla.org clicking on documentation and
going to the linux build page
during this tutorial we will follow this
page step by step
the index on top will allow you to visit
specific steps of the process
there is also a command summary right
before starting which contains all the
terminal commands used during the
installation
once you are familiar with the steps
this may save you some scrolling and
provide with a bigger picture of that
process
there is also frequently asked questions
page in the docs and any issues not
stated there can be solved using the
issues section
github or the carla for room before
starting make sure you read the minimum
requirements to make the build
if your system does not meet these
requirements remember that the release
packages are still an option to run the
karla simulator
first of all let's install the necessary
dependencies for carla and unreal engine
to run
this process is quite straightforward
copy and past a bunch of commands and
simply check that no error message
appears
the only thing to note here is that
there are some commands that change
depending on where
your system is ubuntu 18 or a previous
version
make sure to choose the ones that fit
your system which in my case is ubuntu
now that the dependencies have been
successfully installed there is one last
pre-requirement
in order to make the build we will clone
both carla and unreal engine
repositories available in github
that means you will need a github and an
unreal engine account
also as unreal engine repositories are
private
both accounts have to be linked it is no
headache
simply create the accounts and make sure
to activate them you should receive an
activation mail on the fly
once you have both accounts go to the
personal panel
in the unreal engine website click on
connections
and then accounts there should be an
option to connect
github and unreal engine accounts click
on it and sign in if necessary
it is time to finally start with the
build process
again this will be no headache just a
matter of copy pasting the commands that
appear in the docks first we will make
the build for unreal engine
this has nothing to do with carla the
simulator will run
using the unreal engine editor but
unreal engine is a much bigger thing
itself
clone the repository this shouldn't take
long and it will create a clone of the
github repository in your system
the path is stated last in the command
it can be changed but if you do so
make sure to change the following
commands accordingly
get into the directory to make sure that
it exists
now it is time to install a patch that
solves some visualization issues when
using vulkan
again inside the unreal engine directory
copy the commands to download the patch
file and apply it
finally it is time to make the build
this will take a long time probably
around an hour or two but it depends on
your system
run the command and go do other things
in the meantime
when the build is finished test unreal
engine to make sure that it runs
smoothly we will not dive deeply into
this
copy the command line to go to the
specified folder and run the editor
any errors that show during the build of
unreal engine have
more to do with unreal engine than with
carla you can create
an issue in our github site or ask for
help on the carla forum
but we can provide with limited support
here try asking on the unreal engine
forms directly if you have any issues
with the unreal engine build
okay now the time has come to finally
build carla
optionally before starting run the
following command line to download
area 2 and make the process a bit faster
once again copy and paste the commands
to clone the repository
remember that if you change the root or
the name of the directory
the following commands should be changed
accordingly
when the repository has been cloned get
into the root directory and download the
assets
these are stored separately to reduce
the size of the build
the assets downloaded with this command
are the latest stable assets
there is a way to download the latest
assets in development
explained in the updated carla page
though this is not recommended
unless there is a specific reason to do
so as these are still in development and
are not stable this download will take
some time so it is a good moment for a
coffee break
now set the environment variable so that
karla can find unreal engine
and finally make the build first the
client side
and then the server side this will take
long too
especially the server side so you can
rest for now this is almost over
when the simulator starts it will look
gray and dull
leave it there for a while as shaders
etc have to be compiled yet
one last thing before running the
simulation it is very likely that one
default configuration of unreal engine
will make the simulation run really slow
go to the editor preferences performance
section
and disable the use less cpu running
background option
if any issues are good while making the
build remember that you can check our
frequently asked questions section
open an issue in github or post in the
carla forum
if there were no problems while making
the build it is time to test some basic
elements
press play to start the simulation and
then run the following commands
to spawn some vehicles and pedestrians
and create a weather cycle
now we have a karla town with some life
and ambience in it
once you have finished with the karla
build it is time to have some fun
play around with the simulation read our
docs especially the first steps on the
python app reference
and follow other tutorials