hello I'm Pierre malapit of the Karla
team and I'll be talking about SNL
runner also this talk is highly related
to another one
about openness scenario first of all
I'll start with an introduction to
senator runner followed by how to run
visa scenarios then we'll dive a little
bit deeper into how is this model
structured as well as how to create new
mercenaries and agents finally this talk
will be concluded with the limitations
and filter work of the sonoran for
version zero point nine point nine what
we mean by an ax scenario scenarios are
complex choreographies of actors that
result in specific situations this is a
novice tend to be focused around one
actor which is the one we'll be
controlling and are meant to force it to
react for example in the in the images
in the right here we can see a deer
which is crossing the road and a flawed
vehicle which is forced to brake to
avoid colliding with it this situation
can can be seen here and it's the one
implemented in a similar manner but in
this case we have substituted the deer
for a pedestrian crossing the road
the senator Rana has several Salah
scenarios or very implemented which have
been taken from the NHTSA procrastinate
this can be generally divided into four
groups the control laws dealing with
lane changes detecting obstacles in the
road and handling all types of set up
situation related to intersections
therefore scenario Runner is the engine
based on Karla that can be used to
execute these types of situation it is
developed in Python and makes use of
Karla's Python API all of these
scenarios are customizable and we also
support the creation of completely new
ones
these can be created directly from
Python or via open a scenario we are
currently supporting an important subset
of features of openness an era 1.0 and
are constantly working on extending that
coverage to install it just clone the
repository install the dependencies and
add the Python path now how do we run a
scenarios in order to run a scenario
honor first of all we have to we must
have a simulation or already going for
Karla then sinner Runner has three ways
of running scenarios first of all they
can be run by themselves in other words
completely isolated they can also be run
inside route or we can run a scenario
using an open area file all of these
cases call to the scenario run a dot pi
file which is the main script of the
repository for the first one here we can
see that the general behavior first of
all only a name is needed when we are
dealing with example scenarios however
if we have created our customer
scenarios we need two more arguments
that specify the path to these two files
the first file is a dot pi a scenario
file and the second one is an XML
configuration file which can be seen in
the image it is this configuration file
that links the scenario name we marked
in red with the scenario file now let's
run an example in this case
one opposite vehicle running red light
with this command we are setting up the
scenario and to check its behavior we're
gonna use the model control now from
this video you can see here the opposite
with the ego vehicle sorry and on the
left and another vehicle on the right
this vehicle on the right will run the
right leg forcing forcing us to react in
this case to brake here we have
activated the model control and as
you'll see in a moment we're gonna have
to break because the the other vehicle
has run the red light then after this
behavior has ended we just have to drive
a little bit before and ending the
scenario the scenario runner offers
several functionalities apart from just
running the scenarios among others we
can choose the water this water is used
based on on the car car car law whether
we can also analyze the scenario
execution exporting its results to a
file or repeat in batch several acts as
scenarios one after another additionally
we're currently working to create a
locking and playback mechanism for the
model control that we caught the
vehicle's controller writing them into a
JSON file and this will be useful in
case we want to repeat the same behavior
again the scenarios can also be run
inside routes in this case the agent is
guided throughout the town following a
specific path
well introduce the ability to run
multiple scenarios during the same
simulation therefore this is a nervous
now half a trigger position and are
activated once the ego vehicle is nearby
to run this the route argument is used
at a scenario dot pi which has three
elements same as before we need a name
and a scenario configuration file
the third element contains information
about the write the route itself
additionally an agent argument is also
needed which is the one the route will
be passed here we can see an example of
around first of all the debug flag has
been activated which are this point in
green and light blue also the red the
red the red points are the trigger
positions of the scenario take a look at
the vehicle on the right which is this
one and this one is the ego vehicle when
it passes near the red block the
scenario is triggered which in this case
spawns a bicycle over here this bicycle
will cross the road when the ego vehicle
exits the intersection and after after
this is scenario is done the ego vehicle
just passes to an another trigger
position and activates as a second
scenario as I said some of the benefits
of roads are the ability to run more
than one a scenario per out additionally
a scenario sapphi default a background
activity which brings the town to life
creating a more realistic situation
lastly routes can also add new materials
which are unrelated to any scenario such
as Lane invasion running a red light or
running a stop sign all of this has been
put put together and with the addition
of some matrix to the criterias we can
now have an overall score for the agent
this has been put together at the leader
board which is an online web service to
evaluate it is tax and I'd highly
recommend to take a look at it lastly
just just a reminder that in we can also
run openness on our files but by using
the openness an error argument but this
will be done at an another talk let's
not focus on the structure of a scenario
runner which can be seen in this diagram
when we are running a scenario the
argument is given by the input commands
tend to be passed to specific files
these files have to be parsed extracting
the configuration of the scenario
with this configuration the world is set
up along with the scenario itself then
the main loop starts which is
responsible of taking all the entities
of the simulation and what then Sara
finishes everything is cleaned up if
there are more scenarios to be run the
whole process is repeated until none and
missing as for the scenarios they all
inherit from basic as an error class
which stores information parts from the
configuration files as well as the
behavior 3 defining the center itself
behavior trees are a way to organize
tasks in a specific order while also
allowing to break down bigger tasks into
a series of smaller ones in the case of
scenarios we've run three elements in
parallel the first one is the behavior
of a scenario which is responsible of
its execution the second ones are the
criteria which analyze this execution
and the third one is a time to time out
which stops the simulation after a
certain amount of time of all of these
elements we only set up two at the other
scenario file
the rest are done automatically but
basically scenario these the structure
of the scenario file can be seen on the
right and has at least these four
functions the first one is as always an
initialization of off of the class this
initialization has to call to basic
scenario initialization the second one
is the image initialized actor function
here we initialize and spawn on all the
actors of the scenario this function is
not automatically called by the
initialization function at basically
scenario the third one creates the the
behavior the behavior three of the
scenario and the last one is the creates
the criterias here we just have to
return a list of all the criteria and
the macabre tree is automatically done
by the basic scenario this behavior
trees are
using the Patricia the pie trees library
these have two elements the behaviors
which are the actions and the composites
which are the decision makers or the
organizers let's start by the second
group these are all run implemented in
by threes and half four types sequence
selector chooser and parallel just to
put on an example sequence and handle
the triggering of different behaviors in
basically in a sequence one after
another
however the behaviors have to be created
we have divided them into three groups
according to the juice the first one is
atomic behavior which are the actions
this would mean something like
accelerate break they in change follow a
vehicle etc atomic conditions with help
with the synchronization of these
actions again an example wait until the
vehicle is in front of another wait
until a vehicle is near a specific
location
lastly the criterion which are used to
analyze the scenario and other
previously mentioned criteria again
college collision Lane Lane invasion etc
all of these have the same structure and
can be seen here in the right as always
first of all an initialization which
must call the its parent class then the
initialize function which is one once
when the behavior becomes active an
update function which one on each stick
that this behavior is active and a
terminate which is run once after the
behavior stops running now here
a list of the behaviors currently
implemented it is a total of 56 and
let's - let's take a look for example at
stop vehicle this specific behavior as
its name implies completely stopped the
vehicle to do so we just have two
parameters the actor which is the actor
will be stopping and a very value this
brake value will be passed to the to the
controller and is the force with which
the brake will happen to do so basically
at the update method we only have to
apply a constant control using this
brake value which makes the actor brake
and when it speed reaches zero it
changes the status of the behavior to
success and the ending ending it now
here as I'd like to explain in a very
general way how to create a new scenario
in this case I'm gonna be creating this
one which basically implies that the ego
vehicle has to merge into a highway with
slow traffic
I'll only explain the Python based
approach but again it is important to
remember that scenarios can also be
created with the open a scenario file as
I mentioned before we only have to
create two files the first one is the is
a dot PI file and the second one is the
configuration regarding the installation
here will have the parameters which will
be filled as the scenario is created in
this case some of the parameters would
be something like the distance between
the vehicle dataflow traffic or the
velocity of this slow traffic while
creating the actors the ego vehicle is
automatically created and we only have
to set its location at the configuration
file for the slow traffic we can either
put exactly the initial positions of
every actor or we can just create two
points the initial and final one of the
slow traffic
then for the slow traffic itself we just
create a loop between these two points
record the positions every certain
distance and then we just spawn or spawn
all of them in punch for the behavior we
only have to activate the autopilot
which uses the traffic manager and
change some of its parameters to for
example avoid them Lane changing and
basically making the slow traffic
disappear then an ending condition is
created which will make the scenario
wait until the eco vehicle has survived
Eve has driven a certain distance lastly
for the criteria we only need to check
collision and that's all we care about
so a collision test issues these results
in something like this right now we have
activated the mono console and we are
slowly slowly moving into the highway in
this case I've detected that behind this
semi tractor there is a space and I can
slowly move into it and and that's it it
is important to remember or sorry it is
important to remember that if this is
too easy or too hard the scenario has
some parameters that can be changed for
example what is the distance between
vehicles in order for another runner to
use an ADA stank these have to be
created in a specific way which is what
we call agents first of all they have to
inherit from autonomous agent and three
functions are needed the first one is
the setup which initializes the agent
parameters the second one is is the
sensors method were the sensors used by
the agent are defined and the third and
last one is run step which is a function
called each tick that will handle the
agent behavior it has two arguments
input data which is the data retrieved
by the sensor
at that frame and timestamp with
temporal information about that frame we
have many examples at sanella runner at
s1 dot Auto agent so go take a look
lastly regarding the current limitations
and future work we have mainly four
topics to discuss the first one is the
documentation which we acknowledge that
it is currently outdated and we are
working on improving it the second one
is related to performance which it is
important to note that when using
complex scenarios they will not be run
in real time we are currently doing an
enormous enormous effort to change this
and explain you can expect very very
good improvements in the future next the
center banner is currently
non-deterministic for running isolated
scenarios with the model control this is
due to how Karla manages client client
communication and we are planning to
change it very soon in the meantime
however an important remark is that the
model control logging and playback
mechanism has been created ensuring that
this deterministic behavior is indeed
and shirt again while we don't have full
support for open SNR 1.0 we are
constantly increasing our coverage of
the features available and we are slowly
moving in into open a scenario this is
all from my part if you have any
questions you can go to the forum or
tour this disco channel and feel free to
ask anything