hello everybody my name is Matt Garcia
engineer at Karla simulator and in this
presentation I will talk about the name
opened rifle standalone mode introduced
it in person $0.99 I will start with a
small introduction and how to work with
it then I will explain a bit about the
generation parameters and what they do
and I will end with an explanation on
how it internally works its limitation
and the future of this mode
this new feature Auto perform full
simulation is starting from a single
open Drive file nobody should not join
with listener assets are required an
open drive file can be easily ingested
by Karla now to this end the simulation
takes an open my file and personally
creates a 3d mesh to run the simulation
with this is done by reading the content
of the open right through Python and
using Karl as the bridge to send this
content to the server side there it is
processed and a message generated from
it also a traffic light and signs are
placed over the map a set of default
spawn points are automatically
distributed and everything is ready to
be used as all the other mobs in Karla
here you can see me using the Python API
to load an open drive file from the
client side the resulting mesh describes
the road to finish it in a minimalistic
manner all the elements will correspond
with the open drive file but besides
that there will be only void traffic
lights stops and yields will be
generated on the fly the listings will
navigate over the sidewalks and the
crosswalks that appear in the map as a
standalone mode uses the XOR direct
directly any issue and it will propagate
to the simulation this could be a
problem especially at junctions where
many lanes are mixed in order to easily
test this feature the config script
under
python api / util has a new argument
Minho's X this expects on a string with
the open D with the path to an open
Drive file if the mesh is generated with
the script the parameters used will
always be the default ones but what this
is basically doing is making a call to
the Python API function generate open
drive world it expects two arguments the
content of the oxide layer file not the
path to it under generation and
digitation parameters that I will
explain in a moment this way you can
make a simple script that automata is
this one test through several open drive
files just with this line of code the
video is shown before is using this
exact function with the file under pass
on API slash util slash open drive
folder called tone big dot X oh dear
this is a new open drive we provide just
for the test of this future these are
all the parameters that can be used to
define the main generation I will now
present the relevant ones instead of
creating the world map as unique mesh
different fragments are created working
smaller prevent unexpected issues also
by dividing the mesh not all of it has
to be rendered at a time this is a step
towards the larger goal what this mode
will be able to generate huge Maps this
will be improved or over time trying to
adjust our split album to fit what
unreal consumes better for performance
reasons in our last iterations victims
have been polished to avoid inaccuracies
the core
especially when even lanes join this
uses a laplacian method to smooth the
vertices on an iterative way for now
this does a good job in other cases
we've tested on but this can also be
improved
since the nature of open drive is to
mainly represent the road and where the
cars can navigate through we have had to
add some safety measures in order to
prevent vehicles from falling off the
map if they go off-road for any reason
we've generated physical worlds on the
boundaries of the road Evelynn the
sidewalks for now desert not generated
in junctions where there is no easy way
to check for boundaries since the road
can't cross each other for that reason
we expanded the lane with injunctions to
fill up holes that can appear in places
of the junction that are not definite in
open drive here we can see the world
pipeline when a new open drive arrived
at the server it starts by generating
all internal map based on open Drive
after that and using all the available
functionalities of the map API and the
Waypoint API our mesh factory generates
a mesh for Adelaide's roads and safety
measurements at this point an obj file
is created this file is sent to the
recast builder in order to a synchronous
Li compute the pedestrian navigation
binary which will be consumed by Karl as
well at the same time we use some rails
API to actually create the mesh from our
format to the engines one and that's it
the server is ready to connect due to a
raucous builder but as to navigation can
be inaccessible for a few seconds or
minutes depending on the size of the
generated map what everything else can
be accessed normally there are still
missing some things like the road
superelevation which is not being
exported by a road runner so we didn't
have any open drive with these features
to test with then the sidewalk head is
also not being generated and synthezoid
walks must be higher than the road level
percolation to be detected we added a
constant head for the time being to
warrantied these collisions
what I showed you was the first
iteration on this mode and will have be
planned for it
starting with opening street maps file
ingestion so you could just download an
awasum from the free open street maps
api and use it directly with Karla so an
open Drive is generated and following
the same procedure we could ingest this
bumped into Karla just think of
automatically imported maps like this
one within a few seconds then why not
importing bigger Maps well that's the
world plans - we're making some tests in
that direction here you have a quick
demonstration a world map of Barcelona
load it into Karla we need to improve
performance to the so we must prepare in
real to the with these maps a new
version of open drive has been recently
released and it comes with more details
and some new features such as toners
we've also planned to increase the
number of things iterated by this boat
like line markings or even buildings
from OpenStreetMaps
so that's pretty much it regarding this
new mode thanks for watching and have a
nice day