[Music]
the carla team is introducing a new
online platform for the consistent
evaluation of autonomous driving systems
the carla autonomous driving leaderboard
[Music]
in this platform agents will be tasked
to safely drive from a set of starting
points to target destinations
following route instructions and
respecting traffic rules
av systems will have to deal with
hundreds of traffic scenarios
inspired by the nitsa pre-crash typology
the carla leaderboard offers two tracks
of participation
the sensors track which lets users
configure a sensor suite
choosing from a range of sensors and the
map track
which in addition to the previous
sensors offers access to an hd map
systems submitted to the leaderboard
will be evaluated according to their
driving proficiency
and the number of traffic infractions
committed users can make the results
public
or opt to keep them private
[Music]
prepare your autonomous driving system
to cope with challenging situations
such as changing lanes in a highway with
dense traffic
taking the right exit on time
yielding to traffic and negotiating the
right-of-way at roundabouts
and responding to sudden maneuvers
performed by other vehicles
your system will have to remain vigilant
to handle dangerous situations where
other vehicles commit infractions
such as preventing a collision as the
red vehicle runs a red light
[Music]
and don't forget to account for
hazardous road conditions
caused by debris road damage or
inclement weather
to participate go to
[Music]
leaderboard.carla.org
you